Clara Fasano Papers
Clara Fasano Papers
1952-1964
Fasano, Clara, 1900-
0.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American sculptor, born in Italy. Photographs of work, 1952-1954; published material including exhibition notices and articles by and about Fasano, 1952-1964; and a biographical sketch.
148975
Biographical History
Clara Fasano (1900-1990) was an Italian-American sculptor, specializing in terra-cotta. Born in Castellaneta, Italy, she studied at the Cooper Union Art School, the Art Student's League and Adelphi College in New York City, and the Colorossi and Julian Academies in Paris. She also studied with Arturo Dazzi in Rome. Like many of her fellow artists of that era, she worked with the WPA/Federal Arts Project; she also taught art at the Dalton School in New York City and at Manhattanville College in Purchase, New York. She and her husband, sculptor Jean de Marco, lived in Greenwich Village, New York.
Over her career Ms Fasano won a prize from the National Association of Women Artists in 1945 and again in 1950, a medal from the Audubon Artists in 1952, a Medal of Honor in 1956, and the National Institute of Arts and Letters awarded her a prize in 1952. Her work has been exhibited at the Art Institute of Chicago, the National Academy of Design in New York City, the 1939 World's Fair in New York City, the Audubon Artists (annually), the National Sculpture Society in 1955, 1959, 1962 and 1964, the National Association of Women Artists, and in Italy, France, England and other major museums in the United States.
She was a member of the National Sculpture Society of New York City, the National Academy of Design, Audubon Artists and the National Association of Women Artists.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Clara Fasano Papers consists of biographical material, incoming correspondence, subject files, and published material.
Biographical material contains a biographical sketch of Ms. Fasano. Correspondence contains three incoming letters. Subject files consists of a notice of a meeting of the Art Educators Association of the City of New York, a photograph of Fasano at work and various photographic reproductions of her work. Published material includes an exhibition notice, magazine articles about and by Fasano with reproductions of her work and newspaper clippings about her work.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by author. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by subject. Published material is arranged alphabetically by type and within that chronologically.
Related Material
See also the
Jean de Marco Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Sculptors; Fasano, Clara, 1900- Archives.; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Italian Americans.; Sculptors -- United States.; Sculpture -- American.; Sculpture, American -- 20th century.; Women artists -- United States.; Women sculptors -- United States.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Photographs.; Artists.; Sculptors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1964, 1968.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Roemnele, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Theurer, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Wood, 1963 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Meeting, "June Gala", undated (Box 1)
  - Photo of, undated (Box 1)
  - Photos of Work
    - "At the Beach", undated (Box 1)
    - "Dolce Far Niente", undated (Box 1)
    - Hamlet", 1954 (Box 1)
    - "Happy Bride", undated (Box 1)
    - "Mario Calling", undated (Box 1)
    - "Neapolitan Tarantella", undated (Box 1)
    - "Penelope", 1952 (Box 1)
    - "The Seeret", 1954 (Box 1)
    - "Siesta", undated (Box 1)
    - "Spring", undated (Box 1)
    - "Washday in the Village Piazza", undated (Box 1)
    - "Woman from Cercaro", undated (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Exhibition notice, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Magazine article, American Artist, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Magazine reproductions of work
    - Sculpture, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Sculpture, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Sculpture, 1962 (Box 1)
    - National Sculpture Review, 1962 (Box 1)
    - National Sculpture Review, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Sculpture, 1963 (Box 1)
    - National Sculpture Review, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Sculpture, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Magazine article about her and others, The Centurion, undated (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings about her and others, 1952; 1961,; 1963-1964 (Box 1)